CAMERON EDEK POOLE

City: SW London | Number: 07930991269 Email: cameron.edek.poole@gmail.com Website: https://www.cedekpoole.com/ Github: https://github.com/cedekpoole

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/cam-edek-poole/

Summary

- Front-end web developer and philosophy graduate with an affinity for problem solving
- Quick and adaptable learner for all things technology related; self-motivated with an ability to work independently and as part of a team
- Completed an intensive 16 week front-end web development certification provided by Trilogy Education, achieving an overall score of 100%
- Check out my portfolio website here: https://www.cedekpoole.com

Technical Skills

HyperText Markup Language (HTML5), Cascading Style Sheets (CSS3), JavaScript, Typescript, User Experience and User Interface Design, CSS frameworks (e.g. Bootstrap + TailwindCSS), version control via git and GitHub, JavaScript libraries (e.g. React.js and jQuery), React frameworks (Next.js), node.js and node package manager (npm), retrieving data via REST-ful compliant requests, test-driven development (TDD using Jest), headless content management systems (e.g. Sanity's CMS) deployment with Firebase, Cloudflare, Vercel and Netlify.

Soft Skills: Creative thinker and problem solver, continual learner, time-management, teamwork, communication and organisation

Projects

Weekly Programming Blog | GitHub: https://github.com/cedekpoole/nextjs-blog-website/ | Deployed: https://webdev-blog-cedekpoole.vercel.app/

A blog website that is updated weekly as means to keep track of progress as a developer and to discuss future project plans

 Technologies used: React.js, Typescript, headless content management system 'Sanity IO' to store blog data, Next.js for server-side rendering and static site generation, Vercel for hosting and TailwindCSS for styling

Productivity App | GitHub: https://github.com/cedekpoole/productive-programming | **Deployed:** https://productive-programming.netlify.app/

Productive Programming is a react app that targets students and developers

Core responsibilities: created functional pomodoro timer and current time widget;
 implemented stack overflow appliance with a search function that allows users to look up relevant questions; built stack overflow and study lounge page; wrote up readme file

• Technologies used: React.js, node.js and npm (howler.js, react icons, react-router-dom, react-bootstrap, date-fns), API calls via axios, Netlify, Bootstrap and vanilla CSS.

Music Dashboard | GitHub: https://github.com/cedekpoole/favourite-music-dashboard | Deployed: https://cedekpoole.github.io/favourite-music-dashboard/

A music app that allows users to effortlessly look up lyrics

- Core responsibilities: Dealt with local storage; dynamically generated favourite song cards (via jQuery); added functionality to said cards (delete songs individually or collectively and stop duplication); general refactoring of code base; formulation of README.md file
- Technologies used: ¡Query, AJAX, Javascript, HTML, CSS and Bootstrap

Experience

Internet Safety Evaluator | Telus International.

Remote: 2021-2022 FREELANCE

Part of the AI community where our analysis of data was used to improve the client's machine learning models. Tasked to help train their content to build better AI; analysed and reviewed potentially misleading data to protect users from viewing unsuitable material on the web. Self-motivation, time-management and critical thinking were critical due to nature of role

Internet Bidding Operative | Crows Auction Gallery

Dorking, Surrey: 2020-2022 FREELANCE

Crows Auction Gallery is a fine art and general auction house, where the main duties entailed moving goods around the property and assisting in online auctions. Bid on behalf of customers on the EasyLive internet bidding platform and assisted with telephone bids as and when required. Learnt to cooperate efficiently and effectively as part of a team

Property Maintenance and Refurbishment | South Terrace Properties Ltd.

Surbiton, Greater London: Jun-Oct 2019

Assisted in the maintenance and refurbishment of a couple of properties. Involved in both the physical and administrative side of the business. Had to adapt and learn quickly on the job whilst also being thorough and accurate. Assisted in renovating three apartments and a garden; worked under the pressure of strict deadlines

Front of House | Raven's Ait Island Bar and Venue

Kingston Upon Thames, Greater London: Apr-Oct 2017

Raven's Ait is an island on the River Thames which specialises in weddings and corporate events. Dealt with groups of 100+ people; involved in setting up large scale events (e.g. Oktoberfest)

Education

Front-End Web Development Certificate - A* | Trilogy Education Services (Nov 2022- Mar 2023)

• Enrolled in an intensive 16 week programme, achieving an overall score of 100%; learnt how to build modern web applications using a variety of technologies (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, git, Bootstrap, AJAX, node.js, npm, react.js, jest (TDD) and enzyme (BDD)).

Philosophy (Bachelor's Degree) – First Class Honours | Newcastle University (2017-2021)